Ana Torres

Core Skill:

Manual Testing

Industry Verticals:

Banking Insurance Media

Programming Languages:

Java

Databases:

Microsoft SQL Server

Tools & Techniques:

TestRail
QC
Git
HTML
IntelliJ IDEA
Selenium
Visual Studio Code

Summary:

A dedicated Manual Tester with over 9 years of experience in Testing, Master in IT architectures. Experience related to software quality, leadership, requirements and process diagrams and experience in different areas: Banking, Pension Funds, Fuel Management Systems. As a complementary activity has experience in leading teams, reporting critical issues, demo of new functionalities and create documentation for users and clients. Strong technical background experience in testing media and financial system, tasks estimation, manual tests creation, maintenance and execution, bug reports processing, creation of intermediate and final reports to the client. Assure testable acceptance criteria, deliver early feedback about project status stages and release features through client Experience coll

Qualifications:

Educational Background:

Master in IT architecture, Universidad de los Andes, 2018 Bachelor's Degree in Electronic Engineering, Universidad santo Tomas, 2012

Certifications:

scrum master, International Scrum Institute, 2022 ISTQB foundation tester, ISTQB, 2020 IELTS, British Council, IDP and Cambridge English, 2013

Spoken Languages:

English, B2+ Spanish, Native

Soft Skills:

Adaptability
Analysis
Analytical Thinking
Autonomy
Client Oriented
Coaching
Collaboration

Curiosity Proactivity

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Industry sector: Web Design						
Senior Tester						
2023-09-10 - Currently						
Project descriptions:	Responsibilities:					
	Execution of functional tests, analysis and reporting of defects					
Programming Languages:	Tools & Techniques:	Testing:				
		JIRA				

Industry sector: Newspaper

Senior manual tester

2019-01-01 - 2023-05-31

Project descriptions:

Project to create and enhance new functionalities for the newspaper markets. This project epic is to migrate the content editor system the company uses in their digital newspapers, Testing scope involved participating in the creation of the test strategy, sprint test plan, test cases, bugs management. Provided training and mentorship to junior testers, resulting in their professional growth and improved team performance. Pursued continuous learning opportunities and obtained relevant certifications such as ISTQB Certified Tester, demonstrating commitment to professional development and expertise in software testing.

Responsibilities:

• Test plan design, scope and construction of test suite • Risk management of the project • Maintain and guide the maintenance of automation suite (selenium, java, cucumber) automation backlog acting as a product owner, helping to define scope, functional and technical tasks across teams based in current test suites of Teams • Lead account testing team • Execution of functional tests, analysis and reporting of defects • Creation of regression and execution suite • Defects creation and management.

Programming Languages:

Java

Tools & Techniques:

Jira, Postman, Cucumber, Selenium

Testing:

Accessibility testing, Automation Testing, Manual Testing

Industry sector: Payments, Healthcare

Testing and certification analyst QA

2017-03-01 - 2018-12-31

Project descriptions:

A retirement fund platform for employees, we as a team build the new brand refresh also created new functionalities according to the roles and plan of each employee; I oversaw quality assurance in the team Also an API was built in order to be used by the Mobile team, we tested this new API using postman as the main tool

Responsibilities:

• Test plan design, scope and construction of test suite • Risk management of the project • Execution of functional tests, analysis and reporting of defects • Creation of regression and execution suite • Defects creation and management. • Demos with the client for new functionalities review

Programming Languages:

Tools & Techniques:

Testing:

Jira, Team Foundation Server, Postman

Manual Testing

Industry sector: Banking

Software QA Tester and certification analyst

2016-03-01 - 2017-07-31

2010-03-01 - 2017-07-31			
Project descriptions:	Responsibilities:		
Responsibilities: • Build of test plan, scope and test cases • Risk management of the project • Execution of functional tests, analysis and reporting of bugs • Testing and certification of bank development projects • Defect management. • Demo of projects to the end user of the application	Testing Project to assure the quality of the new payment channel platforms, design of test plan, test suite, test cases, Regression suite, Reports and metrics		
Programming Languages:	Tools & Techniques:	Testing:	
	Jira, SQL	Backend testing, Manual Testing	

Industry sector: Banking

Software QA and BA

2015-03-01 - 2016-03-31

Project descriptions: • Build of testing matrices and use cases • Execution of functional tests, analysis and reporting of bugs •Leader of metrics. functional tests for Client • Survey and monitoring of defects. • Mapping of banking software process flows • Implementation and design of the second phase of UAT tests (Tampa, EÚ) **Programming Languages: Tools & Techniques:**

Responsibilities:

Server

Project to assure the quality in the migration to the interbank payment's platform, design of test plan, test suite, test cases, Regression suite, Reports and

Testing:

BPMN, Team Foundation Backend testing